It is 11st January
and you are watching the research paper
presentation at ICARRT.
We are a group of four authors represent
for University of Information Technology.
Nowadays, almost every adult has their own
vehicle,
especially in developing countries.
In 2022, there are millions
traffic law violations,
with more than 14,000 traffic accidents
resulted in roughly
6,500 deaths and a vast injured people.
The reason for this case
is that citizens have incredibly low
awareness of the traffic regulations.
Moreover,
there are thousands of traffic rules
that could be challenging for drivers
readers to gain a deep understanding
about transportation law
with a strong desire to support citizens
in achieving fundamental knowledge
about law, concepts and penalties.
We propose a paper Ontology-based solution
for building
an intelligent searching system
on traffic law documents.
Our primary mission is to design a system
that has the ability
to search for penalties, fines
and concepts for road traffic offences.
based on the questions given by users.
Here are the features of our system.
Q&A System.
We will collect the questions from the users and return a list of articles
based on their ranking in similarity
with the queries extensibility,
we developed a subsystem
that could extract and retrieve knowledge
from law documents and questions
automatically.
This would lead
the intelligent keeps learning over time.
Usability
Our model propose
a high usability since the content
is served over the internet
without any further installation
in order to achieve the requirements,
we have adopted Traffic-Rela model
based on the rela model.
It is an effective ontology
for representing the knowledge
of relations in legal domain
and is a combination of three components.
Let's dive into this model.
The Traffic-Rela model has the following
structure C, R and Rules.
C is a set of concepts in traffic domain.
R Is the set of relations between concepts
or fact rules.
Represents the inference rules
to specify the relation between concepts
and penalties.
Concept
Each C and concept has the structure, name
meaning, attributes and keywords.
Name is the name of the concept.
Meaning is the meaning of the concept
Attributes is a list of attributes of concept
Keywords is a list of keywords
related to the concept.
For example, the concept Electric
Motorcycle will be described as follow
Relation
Each relations between concepts in R has the structure
name, conc, meaning, props and keywords.
Name is the name of the relation.
Conc is a list of parameters
as concepts of the relation.
Meaning is the meaning of the relation.
Props are the properties of relations.
Keywords
a list of keywords of the relation.
Take this comply relation as the example.
Rules each rule are in rules
as the form u(r)->v(r).
Where u(r) is the hypothesis facts
and v(r) is the result of rule r
rules could be the combination
of two different rules types
infer and offence
rule infer is a set of rules
inferring the relation between concepts.
Rule offences is a set of rules
determining the offences and penalties.
Following is our searching system
on the traffic knowledge domain developed
based on the model described
To begin with,
user will start by entering
traffic questions.
These queries will be extracted,
classified and augmented before
transmitted to the traffic law model.
This model will combine processed keywords
along with knowledge
base collected from documents and lawyers
to return relevant raw results.
It then will ranking these raw results
and transform to readable response
before return to the users.
Here is our example
for the searching system
with different types of queries
in realistic.
Thank you for your watching
and see you in the next videos.